After we have learned about the bonus search, let's see how to create the algorithm for Biden insertion
in the sea language in an iterative way and in recursively, we will start with the iteratively.
We create the include studio and we create a new method called binary search.
It's returning type and took them to better printers, therefore parametres the end array that we are
going to search inside did the index, which is the value, but the two to go in search for inside the
array.
And we took into the parameter of the inflow and into we will see the function of these variables.
Repeat until the pointer is low and high.
Meet each other.
We see that in the binary search.
We divide the array into two in the middle.
From the middle.
We have the left section and the right section whenever.
Thing that and the low and the high ends of a an array mat.
Then we have only one element, only one element presented and found and remain.
So this element would be that the searched element and it would be found if they are equal.
Otherwise, it will not be equal.
So we get that we cannot search for it because it is not found in right.
What does this means?
We will make it.
It translated into the code the by using the while loop so.
Why low less than or equal to high, then create an integer ment, which is equal to low plus high minus
low over two, if they're at index mid, equal equal to X, then return meant.
So we have found that the heart of that index that we ought to go at the element of at index MIT in
this case.
Otherwise, if the if the array at MIT Index was then X, then make lo equal MIT plus one.
So that array at index meant less than X that we are going to find it then now equal to MIT +1 otherwise
high, equal to MIT minus one.
And this is repeated by a using that iterative way, which is the wide loop that we have created.
Otherwise, if this loop breaks without using and turning anything, then to a return minus one.
So the element is not.
Let's test it by using that main method.
We create that today we calculate its size and index equal to four, we are searching for four for inside
this essay.
Which is present so Inter result equal binary search, we are calling the method miners search and it's
returning type and is stored inside a valuable cold result.
We passed them today with Best X, which is equal to four and zero, which is that low and the high,
which is and minus one.
So this is the array.
This is zero and this is and minus one.
So this is the high and this is the.
If result, equal equal minus one, then not found the rise will be printing, that element is found
at the index and we print the ethics.
Let's see the binary search in see by a recursive way, the same we will create that Int X array and
lo and then tied as parameters and binary search method we return and if high, greater than or equal
to low, then make a mid-tier equal low plus high minus low over two.
This is very important because we have to distinguish between that recursive way and turn it this way
if it is found and the middle, then return if error rate at index equal to the value of the variable
that you are going to search for, then return the mid.
Otherwise reverse.
We will search that left half by changing the array Edmund index mid greater than X, then return binary
search.
This is the recursive method.
This is the recursion used inside recursive way in binary search.
Passed Ray Wood as the X as the low the same, but here made minus one.
Otherwise, we searched the right half by using the return binary search here again in the recursive
way faster a fast x pass high.
And but this is the the trick by using timit plus one as the left.
OK?
Otherwise, if we don't return anything here, we will return minus one, which is four, indicating
that the element is not found.
This is the array.
This is that size and this is this the X that we are going to search for.
OK.
We store it inside.
It's a result variable and we pass Array X zero and nine and minus one.
OK, now a frizzled equal equal minus one in that otherwise element is found at the index.
OK.
So this is for binary search and see, let's solve the exercise in one hundred and three about binary
search in Java.